英国国王亨利五世和法国国王查尔斯六世
于1420年签订了特鲁瓦条约
条约规定法国附属于英国 直至国王死去
随后两个国王相继死去
年仅几个月的亨利六世 成为了英格兰及法兰西的国王
查尔斯七世 法兰西皇太子
则不情愿把国家交给一个小孩或是他老师贝德福德公爵手中
一场血战在所难免 英国随同勃艮第人开始侵略法国
罗亚尔河 这道天然屏障 暂时挡住了侵略者
查尔斯七世避难于希农 他渴望到兰斯去加冕为法国国王
可是兰斯正在英国人的手中
法国正在经历历史上最黑暗的时期
能拯救法国的只有
奇迹
是谁?
Is anybody there?
贞德
Jeanne.
见到你我很高兴 可是你一天来两三次...
I'm always happy to see you, but to keep coming twice, three times a day...
我要忏悔  可你早晨已经忏悔过了
I need to confess.  You already confessed this morning.
我要再忏悔一次
I need to confess again.
什么样的罪孽...
What terrible sin have you committed since then...
让你一天都无法等待?
that can't wait till tomorrow to be forgiven?
我看见一个修道士没穿鞋 就给了他几双
I saw a poor monk without shoes, so I gave him some.
施舍是没有罪过的 贞德
There's no sin in charity,Jeanne.
可那些鞋不是我的  那是谁的?
They weren't my shoes.  Whose were they?
是我爸爸的  我相信他会原谅你的
My father's.  I'm sure he'll forgive you.
他已经原谅我了
He already did.
但我希望耶稣也能原谅我
But I wantJesus to forgive me too.
如果一直祈求宽恕罪过
If we were to ask forgiveness all the time...
那就要在教堂呆一辈子了
we'd spend our whole life in church.
那样不好吗?  不是不好 只是...
Is that bad?  Well, no, but...
你在家快乐吗?  是的 很快乐
Are you happy at home?  Oh, yes, very.
你母亲呢? 她好吗?
And your mother? Everything's fine with her?
是 她好极了
Yes, she's wonderful.
那你姐姐凯瑟琳呢 还一直是你的好朋友吗?
And your sister, Catherine, she's still your best friend?
我姐姐...好极了
My sister's just...She's wonderful.
那你其他的朋友呢? 你常跟他们一起玩吗?
And what about your other friends? You don't like playing with them?
是的 我们常在一起玩
Oh, yes. I play with them, lots.
那一切都好极了
Everything sounds wonderful.
是的
Yes, it is.
那你为什么还总是来这里呢?
Then why are you here so often?
我在这里感到安全 在这里我可以跟他说话
I feel safe here. It's where I can talk to him.
他?
Him?
我也想跟他说几句...
Well, I try to talk to him...
可大部分时候都是他一个人在说
but mostly he's the one who does the talking.
这个"他"是谁?
Who is this "he"?
他没说过他的名字
He never says his name.
那他...
What does he...
长什么样子?
look like?
漂亮极了
Beautiful.
他都跟你说些什么?
What does he say to you?
他说...
He says...
他说我要做个好人...
He says...He says I must be good...
多帮助他人 照顾好自己
and help everyone and take care of myself.
你说他是从天上来的吗?
Do you think he's coming from the sky?
可能吧
Perhaps.
可不管他是哪里来 我觉得听他的没错...
But wherever he's coming from, I think you should listen to him...
那确实是个好建议
'cause it sounds like he's giving you very good advice.
真是 真是好极了!
It's...It's wonderful!
真是好极了
It's wonderful.
贞德
Jeanne.
妈妈!
Mother!
凯瑟琳!
Catherine!
贞德 你还好吧? 他们没伤到你吧?
Jeanne, are you all right? Did they hurt you?
我很好
I'm fine, really.
我们一直在找你 现在到处都是英国人
We've all been looking for you. The English are everywhere.
我去教堂了  是吗?
I was in the church.  Really?
我去找牧师了 你知道他对我说什么吗?
I was talking to the priest. Do you know what he said to me?
烧掉那里!
Burn over there!
以后再说吧 快藏进来
Tell me later. Quick, hide in here.
那你去哪里?  我就在这里 哪儿也不去
Where are you gonna be?  I'll be right here.
我保证
I promise.
噢 那就是我说的战利品了
Well, that's what I call booty.
伙计
Comrade.
这女人还有把剑
A woman with a sword.
你们看
Look at this.
法国男人真是孬种 居然让女人去打仗
Frenchmen are such cowards, they've left all the fightin' to women.
如果那是上帝的意愿 那就没错的
If that's God's will, then so be it.
那正和我口味 我喜欢女人
Fine with me. I love women.
别动 臭婊子
Hold still, bitch.
你扭来扭去我怎么办事儿?
How can I do it if you keep wriggling about?
轮到你们了
Your turn now.
主啊 保佑这些逝者的灵魂吧
God, preserve and bless the soul of this, our dearly departed.
并让我们远离恐惧和罪恶 阿门
Keep us safe from fear and sin. Amen.
开始吧
Come on.
听我说 贞德
Listen,Jeanne.
你姨妈要带你去她家住几星期
Your aunt and uncle are gonna take you to their house for a couple of weeks...
好让我们重建这里
just to give us time to rebuild things here.
明白了吗?
You understand?
上帝 感谢您赐予我们食物
Lord, we give thanks for the food you've given us.
教会我们热爱自己的家园
Teach us always to love this land...
并保护它不受坏人的破坏
and to save it from those who seek to destroy it.
阿门  阿门
Amen.  Amen.
晚安
So, good night, then.
她以后会怎么样呢?  她会没事的
What's going to happen to her?  She'll be fine.
慢慢长大 嫁个好人 生几个孩子 你就别担心了
She'll grow up, find a good man, make him some children. Don't worry.
她是受过伤害 可她活过来了
She's been hurt, but she'll survive.
明天她就会一切顺利了
Tomorrow she'll be as right as rain.
你等着看吧
You'll see.
我要见牧师
I want to see a priest.
为什么非要她去死?  这只有上帝能回答
Why did she have to die?  Only God can answer that.
我知道耶稣说要爱你的敌人 可我做不到
I know Jesus says to love your enemies, but I can't.
我盼着那些英国佬 在地狱受尽煎熬 永不翻身!
I just want the English to burn in hell forever and ever!
我知道你很愤怒 贞德
I realize your anger,Jeanne.
可我们必须学会宽恕 它是很难...
But we must learn to forgive. It's hard...
但报仇是不会带来和平的
but revenge will never bring about peace.
那什么可以呢? 怎样做她才能回来呢?
What will? And what will bring her back?
为什么先死的人是她而不是我?
And why did she have to die in the first place instead of me?
他为什么不要我的生命而要她的?
Why didn't He take my life instead of hers?
都是我的错! 是我回来晚了!
It was my fault! I was late!
她把自己的藏身地方给了我! 可他为什么要救我呢?
She gave me her hiding place! Why did He save me?
冷静些 贞德 冷静些
Calm down,Jeanne. Calm down.
我不会假装了解上帝的意愿...
I don't pretend to know God's will...
可有一点我确信不疑
but one thing I am sure:
上帝这么做自会有他的理由
The Lord always has a good reason.
他选择你可能是因为他需要你
Perhaps He chose you because He needs you...
为了某种更高的感召
for some higher calling.
只要你响应了那感召...
As long as you answer that call...
你姐姐的死就不会是毫无价值的了
your sister will not have died in vain.
我不想等他的召唤
I don't want to wait for His call.
耐心些
Be patient.
我要一直与他同在
I want to be with Him always.
你会一直与他同在的
Soon you will be able to take part in your Holy Mass.
等你可以领圣餐时...
When you eat of His flesh and drink of His blood...
你就将与他同在
you will be at one with Him.
我现在就要
I want to be at one with Him now.
牧师他说什么?
So, what did he say?
他说不管她何时想来教堂 我们就要带她过来
He says we must bring her to church whenever she wants.
他说的容易 反正又不是他来接送
Easy for him. He's not the one who has to do the bringing.
别这么说 这很重要的
Come on. This is important.
我们不能让她离开我们的视线
We mustn't let her out of our sight.
别担心 我会像看自己的影子一样看着她
Don't worry. I will watch her like my own shadow.
我现在就要与你同在
I want to be at one with You now.
给法国皇太子的信
A message for the dauphin of France.
给皇太子殿下的信
A message.
队长 这是给皇太子殿下的信
Captain, a message for the dauphin.
放那里吧
I'll take it.
皇太子殿下! 皇太子殿下!
The dauphin! The dauphin!
路易斯 怎么没去上课?
Louis. Louis. Hey. Shouldn't you be learning your lessons?
我不想上课 我想学搏击
I don't want to learn. I want to fight.
那个你以后会学的 现在还是先学学擦鼻子吧
You will. But for now, you must at least learn to wipe your nose.
有殿下的信
A letter for His Majesty.
又是那自称是洛林处女的人寄来的
Another one from this girl calling herself the Maiden of Lorraine.
我自己不会读么?
I can read for myself, you know?
她说她是上帝派来的 真是吹牛
She pretends she's been sent by God. Charlatans.
没能把她们全都烧死 真是太可惜了
It's a pity there isn't enough wood to burn them all.
她说她明天就到这里了  殿下 您不能见她
She says she'll be here tomorrow.  You mustn't see her, My Lord.
您根本不了解她 甚至不知道她是不是从洛林来的
We know nothing about her. We don't even know if she's from Lorraine.
她从哪里来很重要吗?
What difference does it make where she comes from?
如果她是从勃艮第来的 那就不一样了
If she comes from Burgundy, it makes a difference.
这可能是个圈套 您看 署名为"X"
It might be a trap. Look, signed "X."
"X"算是个什么名字呢?
What sort of a name is "X"?
莫非上帝的使者连自己的名字都不会写?
Or must we assume that a messenger of God can't even write her own name?
殿下 特利莫伊说的很对 她还说她能听见主的声音
My Lord, Tremoille is correct. She says she hears voices.
她可能是个女巫 一个巫婆
She may be a sorceress, a witch.
勒诺尔 在你眼里谁都是巫师
Regnault, you see witches everywhere.
她只是个农民罢了
She's just a peasant.
一个关心国王的农民
A peasant who cares about her king.
她想要我加冕为王 然后为我而战
All she wants is to see me crowned and permission to fight for me.
不只是这样 她要您给她一支军队 军费您出
Not exactly. She wants you to give her an army at your expense.
记住您母亲已经把国库花了个精光了
Bearing in mind your mother stole every last piece of gold in the treasury...
您是冒不起这个险的
I fail to see how you can afford such an adventure.
愿意的话我会见她的
I can see her if I want to.
一半的法国都落到英国人手里了
After all, with half of France in the hands of the English...
我还有什么好失去的?
what have I got to lose?
另一半
The other half.
殿下 您一定不能见她
You mustn't see her, Your Majesty.
她可能是魔鬼派来的
She may be an instrument of the devil.
我倒认为你该见见
Well, I think you should.
这下有趣了
Well, here's an amusing situation.
我深爱的母亲
I would love to know why my devoted mother in law thinks one thing...
跟两个我最信赖的顾问
and my two most loyal and trusted advisors...
意见为何会截然相反
think precisely the opposite.
因为我关心你 过来
Because I care about you. Come here.
你的幸福健康一直是我最关心的事 查尔斯
Your health and happiness has always been my first concern, Charles...
从小到大
ever since you were a little boy.
我比你的生母还要了解你
And I think I know you better than your own mother.
您真这么想?
You think so, eh?
是的
Yes.
比如说 我知道你受心病的折磨
I know, for example, the sickness that plagues your heart.
我知道你很痛苦 因为你要爱你的父亲...
I know how painful it is for you to have loved a father...
但你甚至不知道他究竟是不是
without ever knowing if he was really yours.
我很了解你吧?
Do I know you enough? Hmm?
那些跟这个少女有什么关系?
What has that got to do with this maiden?
由上帝的信使回答你再合适不过了
Who better than a messenger from God to give answers to your questions?
你认为她是上帝派来的?
You think she was sent from God?
你很会看人的 查尔斯
You're a fine judge of character, Charles.
如果她是假的话 你不到五分钟就能看穿她
It'll take you less than five minutes to expose her if she's a fake.
但如果她是真的...
But if she's not...
那她将会给你问题的答案
then she will give you your answers...
还会把皇冠戴在你的头上
and place the crown on your head.
尊敬的夫人 见一个乡下女孩...
With respect to my lady, I think it's going to take more than a peasant girl...
我对你怎么想不感兴趣 特利莫伊
I'm not interested in what you think, Tremoille...
我怎么想也不重要
or even what I think.
那些朴实的百姓怎么想才最重要...
It's what simple people think that matters, and the fact is that...
事实是现在全国上下都在讨论她
simple people up and down this country are already talking about her.
你知道的 百姓总是喜欢相信...
Now, you know what simple people are like...
古老的预言
always ready to believe any old prophecy.
比如这个...
Like this one...
洛林来的处女...
about a virgin from Lorraine...
拯救了法兰西
saving France.
现在...
And now...
那个女孩出现了...
this girl comes along...
正从洛林赶来
from Lorraine.
百姓的心中会迸发出希望的火花
And suddenly, there's a spark of hope in their simple minds.
你不能让他们失望
You shouldn't disappoint them.
如果他们相信她...
If they believe in her...
如果她能重新点燃军队的斗志...
if she can put back the fire in our army...
那我也会信她的
then I believe in her too.
停下!
Stop it!
路易斯 安静一会儿
Louis, be quiet for once.
她来了 殿下  知道了
She's coming, Your Majesty.  All right.
镇定些
Calm yourself.
殿下 我真心劝您不要见这个女人
Your Majesty, I urge you not to see this woman.
绝对是勃艮第人设下的圈套
It all reeks of a Burgundian trap.
占星师告诉我现在是吉时 狮子座和处女座都升起来了
My astrologers assure me the timing is propitious: Leo with Virgo rising.
你看没看过占星图
Have you never noticed on the astrological chart...
处女座就在狮子座旁边知道吗?
that the virgin is next to the lion?
你说她会是刺客?
Supposing she's an assassin?
我亲爱的特利莫伊...
My My My dear Tremoille...
我还不是国王呢
I'm not even king yet.
谁会想要刺杀我?
Who would want to assassinate me?
她来了 殿下 现在就在卫兵室
She's arrived, My Lord. She's in the guards' room.
好的 好的
Fine, fine.
看来我要下决定了
I suppose I shall have to make a decision.
生活为何如此复杂?
Why is life so complicated?
有时我真希望自己是其他人
Sometimes I really wish I could be someone else.
好主意 殿下
That's a good idea, sire.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
让别人假扮作你
Let someone else pretend to be you.
然后看她能不能发现? 真是高明
And see if she can find me? That's a brilliant idea.
如果她真是上帝派来的 她会看出来的
If she's really been sent by God, she'll discover the trap.
如果她是刺客 那她就会错杀他人 实在是高明
And if she's an assassin, she'll kill the wrong man. Brilliant.
请注意!
Please. Please!
我们要玩个小游戏
We're We're going to play a little game.
现在假装我的王位是空的
Now, let us pretend that my throne is empty.
只是假装而已
Just pretend.
谁想当国王?
Who wants to be king?
这画面真令人感动
Now, there's a heartwarming sight.
看看你们哪一个可以蒙混过关...
Now, let us see which one of you could possibly pass...
假扮法国国王
as the king of France.
艾伦 高贵的公爵
Alencon, my noble duke.
忠心的表弟 如此优秀 勇敢 富有
My royal cousin. So fine, so brave, so rich.
实在太有钱了 不能当法国的国王
So very rich. So far too rich to be king of France.
大家都知道 我是全国最穷的人
Everyone knows I'm the poorest man in my kingdom.
吉尔德雷斯 法国的元帅
Gilles de Rais. Marshall of France.
让男人丧胆 让女人喜爱
Formidable to men, fascinating to women.
让所有人恐惧不已
Feared by all.
你坐我的王位再适合不过
You would be perfect to sit on my throne.
只怕您坐得太过瘾
So perfect that you might like it too much...
让我脆弱的心不得安宁
and therefore disturb my my fragile peace of mind.
拉希尔
La Hire.
我愤怒的副将 法国最勇敢的人
My angry captain, and bravest in France.
经历十数场战争 但仍有胆识再杀十几次
Scarred by a dozen wars, but with a heart and a stomach for a dozen more.
你可以巧扮国王  我他妈的当然可以
You could pass for the king.  Damn bloody right I could.
可惜一开口就完了 因为没有人...
Until you open your mouth, because no one...
说话这样子还能扮成法国国王
with a tongue like that could possible pass as king of France.
看来只得由我亲自上阵
It looks like it shall have to be me after all.
为什么不能是你 吉恩·德奥兰?
Why not you Jean d'Aulon?
只有你比我还穷...
The only man who's poorer than I am...
所以我只能信赖你
therefore the only man I can trust.
高贵 正直 聪明
Dignified, honorable, wise.
不正是一个国王的风范?
What more can we ask of a king?
陛下 恕我不敢
My lord, I'm not sure that...
你不准备为国王而死吗?
Are you not prepared to die for your king?
我当然准备为国王而死  那好
Of course I am.  Good.
在死前尽量摆出国王架势 带她上来
Until then, feel free to live like a king. Bring her up.
陛下 你知道我不会玩这种游戏
Sire, you know how bad I am at this sort of game.
假装这不是游戏
Pretend it's not a game.
为皇太子让路
Make way for the dauphin.
母亲?  闭嘴
Mother?  Not now.
我是来见皇太子的
I have come to see the dauphin.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我 我是...
I'm I'm...
最高贵的殿下 查尔斯·德·瓦卢亚...
His most gracious majesty, Charles de Valois...
法兰西皇太子
dauphin of France.
我看得出你是个好人
I can see you are a good man.
可你不是皇太子
But you're not the dauphin.
对不起 我必须见皇太子
I'm sorry to insist, but I must see the dauphin.
不能再耽搁了 他在哪里?
We have no time to lose. Where is he?
他就在这里 你自己找吧
He's here. Find him yourself.
让你看看到底谁有资格做国王
Now you'll see who'll pass for a king.
您不必害怕 陛下
There's no need to be afraid, sire.
我还不是国王
I'm not the king.
您现在还不是 可马上就会成为国王了
I know you're not yet, but you will be soon.
退下 退下
Out. Out.
你怎么知道我是谁?
How did you know who I am?
显然是上帝的指示  神说 "就是他"
Her voices, of course.  "That's him," they said.
"角落里那个大鼻子的"
"The one in the corner with the big nose."
统统退下!
Back off!
敬爱的太子殿下
Oh, my gentle dauphin.
我送来了...
I have a message...
天堂里来的音讯...
from the King of Heaven...
是给您的
for you.
只您一个人
You only.
跟我来吧
Follow me.
殿下 我认为...
Your Majesty, I really think...
亲爱的特利莫伊
My dear loyal Tremoille, I know I can count on you...
你来负责没人来打搅我们
to to ensure our privacy.
我要跟她单独谈
I need to talk to her alone.
他要跟她单独谈
He needs to talk to her alone.
好啊
Fine.
我十岁那年
I was about ten years old.
那天春光明媚
It was a beautiful spring day.
我穿过森林走近道回家...
I was taking a shortcut home through the forest...
突然
when a strange wind...
刮起了一阵怪风
began to blow.
声音很奇特 就像是人在说话...
It was such a strange sound, almost like words...
在召唤我
calling me.
第二次...
The second time...
是在许多年后了
was many years later.
我正从教堂回来...
I was coming back from church, when suddenly...
突然 跟上次一样
the same...
刮起一阵暴风
violent wind.
然后...
Then...
一个奇特的形状...
a shape...
出现了...
appeared...
就在天空的中央
in the middle of the sky.
那个形状...
The shape...
很象...
of...
很象一个男人
of a man.
然后一切都动的飞快
Everything was moving so fast. So fast.
风啊 云啊
The wind, the clouds.
我无法动弹 我无法呼吸
I couldn't move. I couldn't breathe.
我吓坏了
I was so frightened.
他离我...
He was...
如此...
so...
如此的近
here.
那时我明白了上帝选中了我
And then I knew that God had chosen me.
可我不知道他需要我做什么
But I did not understand what it was He wanted me to do.
我的使命是什么? 我要为我的国家做什么?
What was my mission? What could I do to help my country?
可是怎么做呢? 我一无所有 我只是个贫穷的小女孩
But how? I was nothing. I was just a poor girl.
不懂打仗 也不懂骑马
I did not know anything about...about making war or riding.
所以我决定先等待...
So I decided to wait...
没有对任何人提起过这事
and not to speak of it to anybody.
你做的很好 你做的很好
You did well. You did well.
没等多长时间
I didn't wait long.
我象往常一样去做弥撒...
I was going to Mass, like I do every day...
还是那样...
and the same...
一阵怪风...
strange wind...
然后一切都明了了
Everything was made clear.
上帝给了我一个音讯
God had given me a message.
要我传达一个音讯
A message to deliver.
什么...
What...
什么内容?
What was the message?
他说...
He said...
要我从敌人的手中拯救法兰西...
that I must save France from her enemies...
把她重新还到上帝的手中
and bring her back into the hands of God.
他命令我...
And He told me that I...
贞德...
Jeanne...
带您去兰斯的圣坛...
will lead you to the altar at Reims...
在那里您将加冕为...
where you will be crowned...
法兰西...
the king...
国王
of France.
陛下 您还...  我很好
Sire, are you... I'm fine.
这位是吉恩·德奥兰 我最忠诚的朋友 最棒的射手
This is, in fact,Jean d'Aulon, my loyal friend and finest archer.
你来负责照料她
I put her in your care.
在城堡中给她找个合适的住处
Find her suitable lodgings here in the castle...
守护她的安全
and guard her with your life.
陛下 我不需要住处 我们要进军去奥尔良
Sire, I won't be needing any lodgings if we're to be marching on Orleans.
奥尔良已经坚守了半年了...
Orleans has held out for six months...
不急这两三天
so I don't suppose a few days more will make much difference.
好好休息一下
Take some rest.
把包放在这儿吧
Put the bags here.
请接受我的道歉...
Please accept my apologies...
我刚才假扮做...你明白的
for me pretending to be the...you know.
我能喝点水吗?
Do you think that I can have some water?
水 当然可以
Water. Yes, of course.
你去弄些水来
Would you get some water?
还有其他的吗?  我要见牧师
Anything else?  I need to see a priest.
现在?  是的 我今天还没有作忏悔
Now?  Yes. I didn't confess today.
好的 雷蒙德 去请牧师
All right. Raymond, a priest.
还有其他的吗?
Anything else?
我还需要一匹新的战马...
I shall also be needing a new war horse...
一把剑 盔甲...
a sword, armor...
再找位画家给我做面旗帜
and an artist to make a banner for me.
现在?  宜早不宜迟
Now?  Better today than tomorrow.
那可能要花些时间...
This might take a little time...
我会尽力而为的
but let me see what I can do.
还有 再找个能读会写的人来
Oh! I shall also be needing someone who can read and write.
这个我就可以
This I can do.
在英国人来之前 我一直在巴黎大学学习
I was studying at the University of Paris until the English invaded it.
我以为你是个弓箭手  是啊
I thought you were an archer.  Yes, I am.
我是个能读会写的弓箭手 您要写信给谁?
I'm an archer who can read and write. Who do you want to write to?
英国国王
The king of England.
在我到奥尔良之前...
I want to give him the chance to leave in peace...
给他一个和平撤军的机会
before I get to Orleans.
主教和我刚开始 和勃根地人交涉
The archbishop and I have just begun negotiations with the Burgundians.
如果能让他们站在我们这一边...
If we can bring them over to our side...
当然要交涉 不过要有力量才能交涉
Negotiate, by all means, but from a position of strength.
如果英军攻下奥尔良 就没有交涉的余地了
If the English take Orleans, there'll be nothing left to negotiate.
其余国土将落入英军之手
The rest of the country will be theirs.
夫人 这实在太愚蠢
My lady, it will be the height of folly...
让这个孩子率领军队
to let this child lead our army...
以国王的名义出兵 却没有验证她的真正动机
in the king's name without verifying her true motives.
陛下 图洛伊是对的
My Lord, Tremoille is right.
我们必须完全确定 她不是魔鬼的工具
We must be absolutely certain that she is not an instrument of the devil.
这年头有什么事说得准?
How can anyone be absolutely certain about anything?
有时候你该跟着直觉走
Sometimes our intuitions are our best counselors.
在服从直觉之前必须听听教堂的说法
We must listen to Mother Holy Church before we listen to our intuitions.
等等
Wait.
她自称是处女
She claims to be a virgin.
这个我们倒可以检查...
Well, that's something we can examine...
也可以百分之百确定
and be absolutely certain about.
那就查吧
Let's find out.
如果她不是呢?
What if she's not?
如果她不是...
If she's not...
我就亲自杀了她
I'll kill her myself.
没有堕落或奸淫的痕迹
There is no sign of corruption or violation.
她是纯洁无瑕的
She is intact.
你看到的形象 到底穿着什么衣服?
And what, exactly, was this vision wearing?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
这个形象有给你什么吗?
This vision, did it give you anything?
一样东西? 戒子或念珠...
An object? A ring or a rosary...
或任何证据 让我们可以相信你的话?
or anything by which we can verify your claim?
他给我好的建议
He gave me good advice.
你小时候有没有军事经验?
During your childhood, did you have any sort of military experience?
没有
No.
可曾学过剑术?
Are you practiced in the skills of swordsmanship?
没有 但我很会耍棍
No, but I'm good with a stick.
你知道什么是第戎长炮吗?
Do you know what a Dijon Culverin is?
不知道
No.
是大炮的一种
It's an item of artillery.
你怎么可能解除奥尔良围城之急...
How can you expect to raise the siege of Orleans...
你对现代大炮一无所知
if you're ignorant about modern artillery?
到奥尔良的路还很长 我有优秀副将相伴
The road to Orleans is long, and I have good captains with me.
我会学得很快 相信我
I will learn fast, believe me.
我们很愿意相信你 贞德 但我们觉得...
We would like to believe you, Jeanne, but we feel...
如果上帝要我们相信你...
that if God wanted us to believe you...
他就会给你一个神迹
he would've sent a sign with you.
你可以做什么吗?
So, can you do something?
给我们看点什么吧?
Show us something?
这样才能证明...
A sign to prove...
你是上帝派来的
that you are sent by God.
我不是来表演杂耍的
I did not come here to perform tricks.
我...
I...
你们都比我聪明得多
You are all much cleverer than I am.
我是说我大字都不认识一个
I mean, me, I don't know "A" from "B."
但我知道这件事
But this much I do know.
当法国人民血流成河...
While the people of France lie bleeding...
你们还穿着华服坐在这里...
you sit around in your fine clothes...
想欺骗我...
trying to deceive me...
其实你们是在自欺欺人
when you're only deceiving yourselves.
你们自称是上帝的子民...
You say you are men of God...
却看不到他的手引领着我...
yet you do not see His hand in having guided me...
穿过敌国千军万马 为你带来神的帮助
through 500 leagues of enemy country to bring you His help.
这还不能证明吗?
Is that not proof enough?
还是你们需要更多神迹?
Or do you still need more signs?
给我一支军队
Give me an army.
带我到奥尔良
Take me to Orleans.
到时你们就会看到 上帝派我制造的神迹
And there you will see the sign that I was sent to make.
迪努瓦
Dunois.
什么事?  一颗大的 冲我们来了
What?  A big one, straight at us.
哪一边?
What side?
窗户那边
Window side.
什么事?
What?
终于等到好消息了
I have wonderful news, finally.
他派她过来了 谢天谢地 我们有救了
He is sending her to us. Thanks be to God. We're saved.
真是 真是太好了
It's...It's wonderful.
镇静下 伊特兰斯 说清楚到底什么事?
Calm yourself, Xaintrailles. Who has finally done what?
是皇太子 他给我们送来了粮草和军队...
The dauphin. He's sending us food and supplies and an army...
由贞德率领 那个洛林的女子
led byJeanne, the maiden from Lorraine.
是不是很棒?
Isn't it wonderful?
是啊 简直是奇迹
Yes, it's a miracle.
真不敢相信他们派一个女人过来
I can't believe they are sending a woman.
真想知道她衣服是什么颜色的
I wonder what color dress she'll be wearing.
蓝色
Blue.
头发上还系着蓝丝带 用那个来勒死塔尔博特
With a blue ribbon in her hair to tie up Talbot.
有人知道她到底会骑马吗?
Does anyone know if she even knows how to ride a horse?
看来她会骑
She knows.
你们是迪努瓦大人派来的吗?
Were you sent by Lord Dunois?
是的
Yes, we were.
英军在哪里?  到处都是 粮草呢?
Where are the English?  Everywhere. Where's the food?
还在路上 我先赶来了
It's coming. I rode on ahead.
我有消息要告诉英军的将军
I have a message for the captain of the English army.
他叫塔尔博特  我知道
His name is Talbot.  I know.
能带我去见他吗?  他在河对岸
Can you take me to him?  He's on the other side of the river.
那谁让你带我到这边来的?
So, who gave the order for me to be brought to this side of the river?
老朋友 能再见到你这张老脸还真高兴
Hey, my friend. It's good to see your ugly damn face again.
拉希尔 我警告过你不要说脏话  对不起 贞德
La Hire, I'm warning you. Don't swear.  Sorry,Jeanne.
这位是国王的同父异母哥哥迪努瓦大人
Let me introduce the king's half brother, the dogged Lord Dunois.
迪努瓦大人 您能带我去河对岸吗?
Lord Dunois, will you show me to the other side of the river?
等等! 等等!
Wait. Wait!
好啊! 愿意去就去吧! 我可不去
Fine! Go now, if you want! But not with me!
你要对上帝负责 我也要对我的人民负责
You may have a duty to God, but I have a duty to my people.
我的人都快饿死了
And my people are starving.
我要赶紧把粮食运回城去
Right now, I'm going to take the food back to the city.
你镇静些 跟我回奥尔良吧
And if you can please calm down and let me accompany you to Orleans...
很荣幸欢迎你
it will be my honor to welcome you.
主啊
Jesus Christ.
该死的英国佬要付出代价的
The goddamn English will pay for this.
是的 他们会遭报应的 可你要再说脏话 你也会的
Yes, they will, and so will you if you don't stop swearing.
进来 欢迎到我的小店来
Come on. I'm happy to welcome you in my tavern.
快进来
Come on in.
拉希尔 吉尔斯 你们过来看看
La Hire, Gilles, let me show you something.
这里是托勒利斯城堡 河从这里穿过
Tourelles are around here. The river crosses there.
冷静下 你不能怪这些人
Calm down. You can't blame those people.
他们几周前就听说你的事了
They've been hearing about you for weeks.
没什么好听的! 知道为什么吗?
There's nothing to hear! And why is there nothing to hear?
因为我还什么都没做 这又是为什么?
Because I haven't done anything! And why haven't I?
因为你们没人听我说!
'Cause none of you will listen to me!
你何不过来一起讨论?
Why don't you join us?
我们正在分析军情
We're about to discuss the campaign.
对不起
I'm sorry.
从这里开始 塔尔博特在这些堡垒间
So from here, Talbot has spread his forces...
都布置了他的部队
between these forts up here.
据我们侦查 过去几天里...
But in the last few days it seems, according to our scouts...
在这个堡垒处聚集了一些部队
that some troops have been deployed to this fort here.
这个大家伙是什么?
What about this huge pile down here?
那就是托勒利斯城堡 英国人准备以它为基地开展进攻
That's the Tourelles. The English were planning...
于是我们就把桥拆了
to launch an attack from it, but then we broke down the bridge...
是我干的  是的
I did.  Yeah.
这样一来他们会安静一阵子
Which should keep them quiet for a while.
我的预感是...
Now, my hunch is...
他们会从圣鲁普发动进攻
the attack will come from St. Loup, here.
贞德 你有什么看法呢?
And what does Jeanne think?
我没有看法 那是上帝的事情
I don't think. I leave that to God.
我不管这些 我只负责传达音讯
I am nothing in all of this. I'm just the messenger.
那么...
So...
音讯是什么呢?
what is the message?
我们给英国人...
We give the English...
最后一次机会让他们和平撤军
a last chance to go home in peace.
如果他们拒绝呢?
And if they refuse?
如果他们拒绝...
If they refuse...
我们就渡过河...
we recross the river...
攻击这里...
and attack here...
攻击托勒利斯
at the Tourelles.
这根本行不通 托勒利斯是坚不可摧的
That makes no sense at all. The Tourelles is virtually impregnable.
就算我们在河对岸攻击托勒利斯...
If we are on the other side of the river attacking the Tourelles...
可万一塔尔博特从北方攻城 那怎么办?
what's to stop Talbot attacking the city from the north?
有上帝在  上帝 对噢
God.  God. Why, of course.
我们把他给忘了
We'd forgotten about Him.
我真为你们感到悲哀 你们现在可以笑...
I feel a great sorrow for you because you are laughing now...
可明天晚上 你们中就会有人死去的
but by tomorrow night, some of you will be dead.
说实话 我们不能就那样攻击塔楼
With respect, we can't just attack the Tourelles like that.
那是很复杂的事情  那有什么好复杂的?
It's a very complicated matter.  What's so complicated about it?
我怎么说 你们就怎么做 还有比这更简单的事情吗?
All you have to do is what you're told. What could be simpler than that?
我就是一面鼓...
I am the drum...
上帝靠击鼓来传递他的信息
on which God is beating out His message.
他是如此的用力! 我的耳朵都要震聋了!
He's beating it so hard, it's bursting my ears!
你要明白 我们也很难做
You have to understand, it's not easy for us.
我们突然之间要听命于...
I mean, for our pride to suddenly be usurped by...
听命于一个...
Well, with all due respect, by a...
一个小女孩
by a girl.
我明白了
So that's it.
对你来说 我只是个小女孩
To you, I'm just a girl.
你站在我的立场上想想 如果你是我 你会怎么做?
Put yourself in my shoes for a moment. How would you feel if you were me?
我能理解...
Knowing what I know...
感激不尽
enormous gratitude.
这姑娘很倔吧
One hell of a girl, huh?
我警告过你的
I warned you.
我超喜欢她气得冒烟的样子
I do love her when her fire gets well and truly stoked.
我也是
Me too.
大家好 朋友们!
Hello, my friends!
这一路可真不容易啊
What a journey.
可我们还是来了
But we made it.
能重聚在一起 我们好好热闹热闹
Back together again. Let's have some fun.
好啊 我会看起来像个男人的
Fine. I shall look like a man.
住手!
Stop it!
你竟敢阻止我执行上帝的意愿!
How dare you stop me from doing God's will!
他也没让你把头发全剪掉啊!
He didn't tell you to cut all your hair off!
你又不知道上帝跟我说什么!
How dare you tell me what God tells me to do!
不管怎样 既然他不下来亲自剪
Whatever! But since He's not going to come down and cut it Himself...
那至少让其他人帮你剪得合适点!
At least let someone cut it properly!
雷蒙德 把剪刀拿来
Raymond, bring the scissors.
路易斯 把镜子拿来
Louis, fetch the mirror.
别在生气了 冷静些
Stop getting so angry about everything. Calm down.
我很冷静 是上帝在愤怒
I am calm! It's God that's angry.
我现在要写封信
I need to send a letter, now.
好的
Fine.
"致英国国王 亨利...
To you, Henry, king of England...
致自称为法兰西摄政王的贝德福德公爵
and to you, Duke of Bedford, who call yourself regent of France...your siege.
你们要服从上帝的意愿 放弃围困奥尔良
obey the King of Heaven and abandon...
归还你们占领的其他重镇
Give back the keys to the other towns you've taken...
然后返回你们的不列颠岛
and go back home to your island.
致塔尔博特大人 我诚心的请求您为了您手下众士兵的性命
To you, Lord Talbot, I beg you as humbly as I can beg you...
停止任何破坏举动
do not bring about your own destruction.
向我投降吧 贞德 上帝派来的使者"
Surrender to me,Jeanne the maiden, who was sent here by God."
信!
Message!
"如果你不顾我的警告...
"But if you do not heed my warning...
那我们将以法兰西千年来...
then we shall raise such a battle cry...
前所未有的高昂斗志 与你们战斗到底"
as there has not been heard in France for a thousand years. "
大人 信
Sire, message.
"这是第三次 也是最后一次 我给你写信了
"This is the third and last time I will write to you.
如果你中午时 仍然还在...
If you are still here at noon...
我警告你 你将受到毁灭性的打击
I warn you, you will hear from me to your very great destruction.
请尽快回复"
Please give me your answer speedily. "
去你妈的!
Go fuck yourself!
他们说什么?
What did they say?
他们说会考虑考虑
They said they'll think about it.
很好
Good.
可说实话 我觉得他们明天不会撤走的
To be honest, I don't think they'll leave tomorrow.
我等不到明天了
I can't wait for tomorrow.
法兰西正在流血
French blood is spilling.
醒醒! 快点!
Wake up! Hurry!
他们开战了 没有叫我
They've started the battle without me.
马上去战斗 一定要胜利
There's a battle to fight and a war to be won.
他妈的
Damn.
撤退!
Sound the retreat!
我的旗! 把旗给我!
My banner. My banner!
打开大门!
Open the gate!
怎么回事? 谁下令进攻的?
What happened? Who gave the order to attack?
谁知道 这主意真是糟透了
God knows. It was a bad idea.
士兵有没有做忏悔? 我们的牧师呢?
Were the men confessed? Where are the priests?
没带牧师 我们想要发动突袭
We didn't take them. We wanted to make a surprise attack.
迪努瓦 是你下令进攻的?
Dunois, was it you who gave the order to attack?
回答我!  我们能否以后再谈?
Answer me!  Can we discuss this later?
宜早不宜迟
Sooner is better than later.
等等!
Wait!
你会被砍死的!
You'll be killed!
跟我来!
Follow me!
给我来 我会给你们胜利的!
Follow me and I will give you victory!
快关上!
Close it!
收起吊桥!
Close the drawbridge!
到吊桥那儿去!
To the drawbridge!
她要干什么?  都到吊桥那儿去!
What is she doing?  To the drawbridge!
吊桥已经收起来了  一会儿就开了
The drawbridge is closed.  Not for long.
大家冲啊!
Let's go!
这家伙是我的了
That's mine.
真是个大胜仗 是属于你的胜仗
It's a great victory...your victory...
我们一定要坚持到底 把英国军都赶回...
but we must follow it through and pursue the English...
塔尔博特的大本营去 你有什么好想法
back to Talbot's camp unless, of course, you have another good idea.
首先我们调来主力
First, we find the biggest army we can.
然后打回奥尔良  可是桥已经拆了啊
Then we return to Orleans.  The bridge has been pulled down.
英国人正在修呢  你怎么知道的?
The English are rebuilding it.  And how do you know?
你有你的军师 我有我的
You have been with your counsel, and I have been with mine.
快点! 快!
Come on! Hurry up!
小心伺候我的宝贝
Be careful with my baby.
那就是塔楼了  真是不赖
That's the Tourelles.  Wonderful.
队长!
Captain!
看来是那个法国小娘们带人来了
Looks like the froggy whore's coming to pay us a visit.
我去告诉格拉斯代尔
I'd better tell Glasdale.
把马都拴在那边
Let's put the horses over there.
神父们 请为他们祈祷
Fathers, please, bless them.
请为他们祈祷  好的
Please, bless them all.  We will.
不能再像早上那样了 我们要计划的再周密些
Let's plan this attack a little more carefully than this morning.
说的对
Good idea.
大人
Sire.
有客人来访
We've got, uh, visitors.
格拉斯代尔!
Glasdale!
你听见了吗?
Do you hear me?
你可以咒骂我...
You, who call me a whore...
而我为你的灵魂感到悲哀...
I feel pity for you, for your soul...
为你手下士兵的灵魂感到悲哀!
and for the souls of your men!
投降吧! 向上帝投降吧!
Yield! Yield now to the King of Heaven!
回到你们的岛国去!
Or go back to your island!
你还是回到你的猪圈去吧!
And you, go back to your pigsty!
在城墙布防
Man the walls.
今天早上...
This morning...
上帝赐予了我们一场胜利
God gave us a great victory.
可那根本无法跟接下来的胜利相比拟
But it is nothing compared to what He is ready to give us now.
我知道你们已疲惫不堪
I know you are all tired and hungry...
可我向你们发誓...
but I swear to you...
即使那些英国人长着三头六臂...
that even if these English were hanging from the clouds by their fingertips...
我们也一定会在天黑前打得他们落花流水
we would pull them down before nightfall.
现在...
Now...
所有爱我的人...
let all those who love me...
跟我冲啊!
follow me!
Follow me!
白费劲了吧?
You were saying?
冲啊!
Come on!
我去右路  我去左路!
I go right.  I go left!
冲啊!
Come on!
快把油罐搬来!
Get that fucking pot of oil up here now!
推快点!
Get that fucking thing moving!
快点! 快点搬哪!
Come on! Move that fucker faster!
模样是不错
You're beautiful.
现在该看看你威力如何了
Let's see if you're powerful.
别傻愣着!  那做什么?
Do something!  Like what?
我不管! 别呆着不动!
I don't care! Do something!
发射!
And fire!
Fire!
搞什么?
What the fuck?
太高了 装弹!
Too high. Reload!
快离开这里!  他们在哪儿?
Get out of here!  Where are the men?
在这你会死的! 快离开!
You're gonna get killed! Get out of here!
来啊 打啊!
Come on, fight!
发射! 打啊!
Go! Come on, fight!
快搬炮来!
Bring the culverin!
闪开!
Get out!
我要到前面去!
I'm going up the side!
贞德!  别管我!
Jeanne!  Leave me alone!
快啊! 冲啊! 冲啊!
Hurry! Come on! Come on!
好极了!
Yes!
让你抢先把她杀了! 将军!
Hey, you just killed my woman! Captain!
见鬼去吧
Go to hell.
快叫医生来! 医生!
Call the physician! The physician!
他妈的!
Damn it!
路易斯 快叫医生来
Louis, find the physician.
得把箭拔出来
We have to take out the arrow.
那她会失血过多而死的
She'll bleed to death.
老天 一定得救救她
There must be something we can do for her, for Christ's sakes.
好啊 你去祈祷吧  说的对
Yes. You can pray.  Good idea.
我发誓我这辈子再也不说脏话了
I swear that I will never swear again in my life...
只要你能救她的命
if You save her life.
可我警告你 如果你没救活她...
But I'm warning You, if You let her die...
那你就是天下最...
then You're the biggest...
不要说脏话  还真灵啊
Don't swear.  He heard me.
你们...
Why...
你们为什么不去战斗?
Why aren't you fighting?
你受了重伤
You've been badly wounded.
没关系的...没  是中了箭
It's nothing. It's... It's an arrow.
伤得很深
And it's in deep.
医生来之前你要挺住
You must stay still till the physician arrives.
医生来了也是浪费时间 我们还是试试这个符咒吧
Physicians are a waste of time. We'll have more luck with this charm.
阿金库尔战役时 就是它救了我
It saved my life at Agincourt.
我宁死也不靠这种魔咒
I'd rather die than use magic.
如果再不拔出箭 你就死定了
You will die if that arrow stays in you much longer.
这下好了 讨厌的东西没了
Well, at least this won't bother us anymore.
我们去战场吧!
Now, let's go to the battle!
拜托!
Please!
她还真是够疯狂的
She's nuts.
你冷静点 你必须休息
You must stay calm. You must rest.
好 我休息
I'll rest.
可你们都要...
But you have to...
答应我
promise me...
你们都返回战场上去
that you'll...that you'll go back to the battle.
我答应你
I promise.
快点!
Hurry!
快! 救救她!
Quickly! Do something!
她睡着了
She's sleeping.
什么?
What?
回来啊! 干吗跑啊?
Come on back! Why are you running away?
贞德还活着  很好
Jeanne is alive.  Good.
我们要加强进攻  撤退
We have to press on the attack.  Sound the retreat.
我答应了贞德要继续战斗的  我可没这么说
I promised Jeanne we'd fight on.  I made no such promise.
晚上撤退  不 她不是这么下的命令
Sound the retreat for the night.  No, that was her order.
我已经受够她的命令了!
I'm fed up with taking her orders!
她还说过会在天黑前打败英军!
She swore she'd defeat the English before nightfall!
可她却去瞎逞英雄 还差点死了!
Instead, she goes and plays the fool, gets herself nearly killed!
你看! 看看我们现在的处境!
Look! Look at the mess we're in!
这都是她的错! 不是我的错!
That's her mess, not mine!
如果没有她 我们的情况不会这么糟
We are worse off than if she'd never come at all.
现在都听我的! 撤退!
Now do as I say and sound the retreat!
你们去哪儿啊? 回来啊!
Where are you going? Hey, come back!
回来接着打啊!
Come back and fight!
你在做什么?  给英国佬写信
What are you making?  A message for the English.
士兵们怎么说?
So, what are the men saying?
她是上帝的恩赐
She's a gift from God.
甚至有些人称她是圣人
Some even call her a saint.
就算去地狱 我也愿意陪着她  她叫你去 你真的去吗?
I'd gladly follow her through hell.  Will you go that far if she asks you?
当然会去 又不是没去过
Of course I will, and I've been there before.
有件事情我闹不明白
There's one thing I don't quite understand.
既然她是上帝派来的
She's been sent to us by God.
上帝怎会能让她受这么重的伤呢?
Why does He allow her to be wounded so badly?
那还不如问 她究竟是不是上帝派来的?
Maybe the good question is, is she really sent by God?
这谁会知道?
Who knows?
上帝知道
God knows.
这女人还有把剑
Ooh. A woman with a sword.
你弄坏了大爷的心情
You've hurt my feelings.
法国佬们!
Frenchies!
你们的宝贝天使怎么了?
What happened to your precious angel?
啊? 法国佬们! 法国佬们!
Huh? Frenchies! Frenchies!
我告诉你们吧!
I'll tell you what happened!
我们把那个小娘们送回地狱去了...
We sent the little bitch back to hell...
这样她就能找魔鬼寻欢了!
so she can go fuck with the devil!
你们现在打算如何啊? 法国佬们
What are you gonna do now, Frenchies?
出来打一仗如何啊? 来啊!
Why not come out and fight? Come on!
来啊! 浑小子们! 醒醒吧!
Come on! Bastards, wake up!
是不是正忙着祷告呢
Or are you too busy praying...
以为那样做 那小娘们就能复活了?
to bring your little fucking witch back from the dead?
听见了吗?
Do you hear me?
我听见了!
I hear you!
我还活着!
I'm alive!
或许上帝能宽恕你的亵渎...
May God forgive your blasphemy...
可我决不原谅
for I never will.
决不原谅!
I never will!
你在干什么? 你需要休息
What are you doing? You need to rest.
必须把战士们都叫醒!
We must wake up the soldiers, now!
好战士们 醒醒!
My fine soldiers, wake up!
准备战斗! 准备战斗!
To arms! To arms!
醒醒! 醒醒! 准备开战了!
Wake up! Wake up! We must fight the battle!
战士们! 战斗就要开始了
My fine soldiers, the battle has begun!
醒醒! 时机已经来到了!
Wake up! The time has come!
战斗就要开始了!
The battle has begun!
准备战斗!  什么?
To arms!  Yes?
士兵们 把这座塔拉起来! 现在!
My soldiers, we need this tower up! We need this tower up, now!
用力拉啊!
Pull!
这是干什么?  我们把塔还会去
What's going on?  We're taking back the Tourelles.
全体准备!
Get ready!
去叫醒格拉斯代尔
Go wake up Glasdale.
你这是干什么?  给格拉斯代尔送个信儿
What are you doing?  Sending a message to Glasdale.
就用它?  是的
With that?  Yes.
可你把它的背面冲向前面了
But you've got it back to front.
听着 我知道自己在做什么
Listen, I know what I'm doing...
要么过来帮把手 要么就回去睡你的觉去
so either lend a hand or get back to bed.
我也要给格莱斯代尔送个信儿了
I'm going to send a message to Glasdale too.
大人?
My lord?
何事?
What?
那个法国女人又活过来了
The French witch, she's back from the dead.
快点 士兵们!
Hurry up, men!
我们还是再仔细考虑考虑吧
Don't you think we should take some time to think about this?
宜早不宜迟
Sooner is better than later.
准备战斗! 准备战斗!
To arms! To arms!
早上好
Good morning.
用这个
This one.
她到底耍的什么把戏?
What the fuck is she playing at?
我不知道! 问题是她现在在干啥?
I don't know! The question is, what is she doing now?
她什么都不跟我们商量 我们怎么做事?
How can we plan anything if she doesn't consult with us?
我们昨天跟她商量了吗?  少提这茬
Did we consult with her yesterday?  Don't even start.
你昨天也是同意进攻的  是啊 可那不算
You agreed to attack yesterday too.  Yes, but that doesn't count.
为啥?  因为我一辈子都同意进攻
Why is that?  Because I always agree to attack.
准备战斗!
To arms!
疯婆子
Crazy bitch.
她连怎么用都不知道
She doesn't even know how to use it.
天哪!
Oh, my God!
靠! 快关城门!  关城门!
Fuck! Close the doors!  Close the doors!
开门啊!  给"箭猪"装箭!
Open the door!  Load the porcupine!
用力拉!
Pull!
拉!
And pull!
快! 动作快点!
Come on! Hurry up!
来吧!
Come on!
不要企盼奇迹 待在这儿
Never wait for miracles. Stay there.
法国娘们! 来抓我啊!
French whore! Come and get me!
还等什么呢?
What are you waiting for?
什么事? 贞德!
Yes? Oh,Jeanne!
准备火箭手! 烧城门!
Find your archers and burn that door!
马上办!
Right away!
推!
Push!
城门准备!
Prepare the gate! Come on!
弓箭手就位!
Position!
放!
Fire!
拿水来!
Water!
放!
Fire!
上帝啊!
Oh, my God!
杀了她
Kill her.
他妈的 装箭!
Fuck. Reload!
再来些弓箭手!
More archers!
漂亮
Perfect.
再来些弓箭手!
More archers!
帮帮我!
Help me!
集合你的人! 准备攻城车!
Get your men! We'll load this up as a battering ram!
早做好了
Already done.
怎么了?  没事
What?  Nothing.
那帮我抬这些人
Help me with these men, please.
是的
Yes.
遵命
As you command.
等等 你要干什么?
Wait. What are you doing?
撞开城门 你不是这么想的吗?
We're going to open that door. Isn't that what you want?
快给我让开!
Get out of my fucking way!
把锅加满!
Fill the cauldron!
该死的法国人! 看我怎么收拾你们
Fucking French! What the fuck do you know about me?
装箭 装箭!
Reload. Reload!
快把锅倒满! 你们等什么呢?
Fill the fucking cauldron! What are you waiting for?
来人! 来人!
More men! More men!
预备!
Ready!
倒油! 倒油!
Pour the oil! Pour the oil!
你在干什么? 贞德
What are you doing,Jeanne?
我在玩
I'm playing.
你对我做了些什么? 贞德
What are you doing to me,Jeanne?
听见我说了吗?
Do you hear me?
你怎么了?
Are you all right?
能听见我说话吗? 冷静一下
Do you hear me? Calm down.
结束了
It's over.
我们赢了
We won.
赢了?  是的
We won?  Yes.
臭婆娘
Fucking bitch.
我的朋友! 我的战友! 快过来
My friend! My soldier! In my arms.
我们赢了?  赢?
We won?  Won?
错了 贞德 怎么能用这个小词呢
No. No,Jeanne. So small a word will never do.
这是胜利!
This is victory!
这是荣誉!
This is glory!
你怎么了?
What's the matter?
这就是荣誉?
This is glory?
不要紧的
Doesn't matter.
这不可能
This is not possible.
It is not possible.
你看起来很失望啊 这不是你想要的?
You look disappointed. Isn't this what you wanted?
不 不该是这样的
No. Not like this.
几周来你一直渴望着这一切
For weeks you've been asking for this.
现在你得到了
Well, now you have it.
你要干什么?  没什么
What are you doing?  Nothing.
我只是想要他的牙
I'm just taking his teeth.
你不能为了想要一个人的牙就杀了他
But you just can't kill a man for his teeth.
为什么不? 他的牙很不赖
Why not? He has good teeth.
你...你不能这么做!
Because...Because you can't!
那这一切又是什么?
What about all this?
那不一样
But that's different.
我们战斗是为了我们的理想
I mean, we were fighting for a cause.
我不是 他是我的俘虏
Not me. He's my prisoner...
要不要他的牙是我的事
I can take his teeth if I want to.
你不能这样! 住手!
No, you can't! Stop it!
给 拿着!
Here. Take this!
现在他是我的了 而你
He's mine now. Here, you.
走吧
Go.
做的好啊 那其他战俘怎么办?
Bravo. And what about all the other prisoners?
全放他们走?  我不知道
Do we let them go too?  I don't know.
也许吧
Maybe.
我们必须去忏悔 我们必须去忏悔
We must confess. We must confess.
我们要做忏悔 所有人都做
Please, we have to be confessed. All of us.
我知道这不符合一般习惯...
I know this is not normal custom...
可是
but, uh...
一切会好起来的 他会听我们忏悔的
Everything's gonna be fine. He's gonna confess us.
跪下 都跪下
Kneel. Kneel.
阿朗松带来个坏消息
Alencon brings bad news.
上千名英军正在河岸远处集结
Thousands of English are forming up on the far side of the river.
我们要清点一下人数 准备作战了
I think we should count our men and get ready.
我们走
Let's go.
我过去
I'll go.
一个人过去
Alone.
告诉你们的国王 亨利!
I have a message for your King Henry!
这是上帝给他的音讯!
It is a message from God!
回家吧!
Go home!
静静地回去吧!
Go now, in peace!
你们不走的话 这里就将是你们的葬身之地!
If you do not go now, you will be buried in this field!
我已经看够了鲜血!
I've seen enough blood!
可如果你们还想看...
But if you want more...
那我也无法阻拦你们!
I can't stop you!
我要说的是 看到的只会是你们的鲜血...
I can only warn you that it will be your blood...
不会是我们的!
not ours!
我等你们的答复
I'm waiting for your answer.
不要期待奇迹 准备战斗
Never wait for miracles. Stand by to attack.
求你了
Please.
主啊...
My Lord...
求你了
please.
那就是他妈所谓的奇迹了
Now that's what I call a goddamn bloody miracle.
她跨着白色战马 孤身前往...
She was on her white horse alone...
面对全部英军 逼退了他们...
facing the whole English army, and she drove them away...
现在奥尔良自由了
and now Orleans is free.
我们失去了奥尔良
We lost Orleans.
我要抓住那个女孩
I want that girl.
我要烧死她
I want that girl burned.
我能见见裁缝吗? 太紧了 我喘不过气了
May I see the seamstress? It's too tight. I can't breathe.
那也算是皇冠? 没有更好点的吗?
That's meant to be a crown? Don't you have something more regal?
英国人把真的拿走了
The English took the real one.
浑身脏的时间太长了 我都忘了干净是什么样了
It's been muddy so long I forgot how good it looked cleaned up.
你里面也弄干净了吗?
But did you remember to clean up what's inside as well?
我要的是个宏大的加冕礼 你这算什么?
I ask for a grandiose coronation, and this is what you give?
真是彻底的失败啊!
This whole thing is going to be an utter fiasco!
你只给我三天时间准备 你父亲的加冕准备了三个月
You gave me 3 days to prepare. Your father's coronation took 3 months.
说的对 看来我们应该推迟了
He's right. We should call for a delay.
没时间了 我们不能停下来
No time. We can't hold up the ceremony.
谁知道英国人什么时候还会回来
No telling when the English might come back.
回来好啊 让他们瞧瞧法国真正的国王
Let them come. Let them see who is the true king of France.
该死的英国人 我们本该在巴黎圣母院举行仪式的
Those damn English. We should be doing this in Paris in Notre Dame.
那会比这个隆重两倍
It is much more prestigious and twice as big.
大小不重要 神圣才是关键 对吧主教?
It is the sacred place that matters, not the size. Correct, Bishop?
是的夫人 法国的国王必须...
Yes, my lady. True kings of France must be anointed...
在伟大的兰斯大教堂施以涂油礼
in our great cathedral of Reims with the holy oil of Clovis.
阁下! 好像没有油了
Your Grace! There can be no anointing.
你说什么呢?  施礼用的油不见了
What are you talking about?  The holy oil of Clovis is all gone.
不见了? 不可能
Gone? That's impossible.
那可是神油 是不会用尽的
It's a magic oil. A miraculous oil. It can never be exhausted.
您自己看看  有问题吗?
Look for yourself.  Problem?
这就奇怪了
I just don't understand.
上次我看的时候 油还满满的
The oil of Clovis. It was quite full the last time I saw it.
上次是什么时候?  查尔斯六世加冕的时候
And when was that?  At the coronation of King Charles VI.
三十年前? 那它消失有什么奇怪的?
Thirty years ago? Does it surprise you it's gone?
你不明白
But you don't understand.
那是神油 非比寻常
It's no ordinary oil. It's a miraculous oil.
是天堂来的白鸽子送来这里...
It was brought by a white dove from heaven...
给国王加冕用的
to crown King Clovis in this very cathedral.
你干什么?  完成这个奇迹
What are you doing?  Performing a miracle.
神油在此 万能的主保佑...
With this sacred oil, blessed by the hand of God the Father Almighty...
向你施以涂油礼 查尔斯·瓦罗亚...
we do anoint thee, Charles Valois...
成为法兰西至高无上的国王...
to be sovereign lord and king of this great kingdom of France...
在你的有生之年...
charging that ye should defend the faith of our Mother Holy Church...
维护教会的信仰
as long as ye shall live.
阿门
Amen.
国王万岁!
Long live the king!
贞德 你没事吧?  是 我没事
Jeanne, are you all right?  Yes, I'm fine.
你盯着我干什么?  你腿上中箭了
Why are you staring at me?  You have an arrow in your leg.
知道了
So there is.
可那不耽误你接着攀墙啊!
But that doesn't stop you from climbing!
快去攀! 快去!
Well, climb! Go! Go!
把这支箭拔出来
Take this arrow out.
留神!
Look out!
小心点!  贞德 士兵已经疲惫不堪了
Be careful!  Jeanne, the men are exhausted.
我知道 可敌人正在撤退 巴黎就要是我们的了
I know, but so is the enemy. They're falling back. Paris is ours.
贞德 我们人不够了
Jeanne, we are not enough.
那就把援军调过来
So bring up the reinforcements.
援军? 哪儿有?
Reinforcements? Where?
就在我们后面
Right behind us.
迪努瓦带着他的一万人马
Dunois with another 1 0,000 men.
贞德 你自己回头看看  只看前方 不要回头
Jeanne, look behind you.  Never look behind. Only ahead.
你知道怎么数数吗?
Do you know how to count?
我当然会! 把他们调过来!
Of course I do! So, bring them up!
贞德 那可不是一万援军!
Jeanne, that is not 1 0,000 reinforcements!
那只是一百名...
That is 100...
忠心无比但又疲惫不堪的士兵!
very loyal but very tired soldiers!
迪努瓦呢?
But where's Dunois?
国王答应给我的军队呢?
And where are the men the king promised me?
他跟本就没派军队! 你还不明白吗?
He never sent them! Don't you understand?
他不想再打仗了
He doesn't want this war anymore.
他已经得到王冠了 他已经满足了
He has his crown now. That's all he ever wanted.
可是那些声音 他们明明答应我的
But my voices, they promised me.
去你的奇怪声音吧!
To hell with your voices!
面对现实吧!
It's time to face facts!
我们不该来这儿!
We have nothing to do here!
谁都不该来!
None of us!
甚至是你
Not even you.
你们不再相信我了吗?
You don't believe in me anymore?
贞德 我们当然还相信你
Jeanne, of course we still believe in you.
如果我说了算 我要把英国人全赶到海里去
If it were up to me, I'd chase every goddamn Englishman into the ocean.
可我们说了不算
But it's not up to us anymore.
国王说了才算
It's up to the king.
我们回去吧 贞德
You should go home,Jeanne.
她要的军队太庞大 我们无法负担
We cannot possibly afford to pay for the size of army she's demanding.
那女孩疯了
Girl is crazy.
她在奥尔良的胜利是个奇迹
Her victory at Orleans was a miracle.
可我们建造法国的未来是不能靠奇迹的
But we can't wait for a miracle when we build a future for France.
巴黎一战是场灾难
Paris was a disaster.
上帝已经不跟她在一起了
God wasn't with her then.
如果上帝抛弃了她 我们该怎么办?
If God deserts her, what do you think we should do?
你为什么出卖我? 再给我几百人巴黎就是我们的了
Why did you betray me? Paris was ours. All I needed was a few hundred men.
为什么你不派给我军队?  给你?
Why did you take the army you gave me?  Gave you?
我当时的意思可不是这个  那你什么意思?
I wouldn't quite put it that way.  So how would you put it?
我们 很感激...
We are, of course, enormously grateful...
你过去所做的贡献
for your past efforts...
现在你的任务已经完成了
but now your task is done.
是该进行和谈的时候了
Now is the time for negotiation.
只有战争才能从英国人那里得到和平
Peace will only be got with the English by the end of a lance.
你就这么嗜血如命? 你很享受吗?
Why are you so bloodthirsty? Do you enjoy it?
外交手段要更文明...
Diplomacy is far more civilized...
更安全 也更廉价
far safer and far cheaper.
这是受围困的城来的信 那里的百姓都要饿死了...
I've letters here from towns under siege, where your people are starving...
祈求上帝去帮帮他们
begging God on their knees to help them.
我要去给他们答复 你去要阻拦我?
I'm here to answer their prayers. And you want to stop me?
法国不是属于你个人的 查尔斯
France does not belong to you, Charles.
她是属于上帝的
She belongs to God.
她能乖乖回家就好了
If only she would just go home.
那我现在怎么办?
So what am I supposed to do now?
你们有得到什么启示吗?  已经好几周听不见他们的声音了
What do your voices say?  They haven't spoken to me in weeks.
是从加冕礼以后
Not since the coronation.
没有任何征兆
No signs, nothing.
或许他们的沉默就是一种指示
Maybe their silence is a sign.
就是让你回家去  不是的
Maybe it's a sign to go home.  No.
还不是时候 我的使命还没有完成
It's not time yet. My mission isn't over yet.
我还有好多要做的事  可你怎么做...
There's still more I have to do.  But how do...
你怎么知道...
How do you know that these...
那些声音就是对你说的?
these voices aren't just really you?
是对我说的 上帝就是这样指示我的
Well, they are me. That's how God speaks to me.
如果你仔仔细细的听 你也能听见的
Even you could hear them if you listened hard enough.
你说的太容易了
You make it sound so simple.
连你也不再相信我了
So even you don't believe in me anymore.
贞德 我比任何人都信任你
Jeanne, I believe in you more than anyone.
我只是希望...
I just wish I could...
我能帮帮你
help you.
想帮我 做一件事就可以了
There is one thing you can do if you want to help me.
告诉我
Tell me.
让国王把他许诺的军队给我
Tell the king to give back the army that he gave me.
我们必须阻止她 陛下
We have to stop her, Your Majesty.
如果她率领军队 攻打勃艮第...
If she raises an army and attacks the Burgundians...
那几个月的和谈就白费了
months of negotiations will have been in vain.
贞德为我们已经做的够多的了
Jeanne has done so much for us.
我自己也是十分敬佩她
I can assure you, the maid has no greater admirer than myself.
可不论我们个人怎么想 我们也不能...
Whatever our personal feelings, we cannot allow her to conduct...
让她为了报仇去打仗
her own private war.
为了国家着想您不能让她去康比涅
For the sake of the kingdom, you must stop her from going to Compiegne.
我阻止不了她
I can't stop her.
如果你不原意的话 勃艮第人会原意帮您的
Well, if you don't, I'm sure the Burgundians would be happy to oblige.
或许他们可以在康比涅抓住她...
If they capture her at Compiegne...
那就没人会怪罪我们了
No one could blame us.
可那好像是我们出卖了她
But it could sound like we betrayed her.
不 没有  上帝啊 不是
No, never.  Good heavens, no.
别担心 查尔斯
Don't worry, Charles.
如果上帝仍然与她同在 她会胜利的
If God is still with her, she will be victorious.
可她的军队是那么少
But her army's so much smaller.
那她的信仰可要更强烈才行
Then her faith will have to be bigger.
你干什么? 快开门  我不能拿自己的城冒险
What are you doing? Open this gate.  I can't risk the safety of my town.
拿着我的旗!
Take my banner!
上帝啊
My Lord.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
你幻想中的死亡竟是遍地长满了草
Your romantic vision of death with all that grass growing everywhere.
我必须承认你的想象力是很强
I must admit, you have a big imagination.
可还是不够
But maybe not big enough.
死亡其实很简单
Death is much more simple.
几个月后会变得更有趣些
After a few months, it gets more interesting.
一年后就会变得...
Then after a year, it finally becomes...
虚无缥缈
romantic.
你是谁?
Who are you?
不喜欢我这张脸?
You don't like my face?
这张你或许会喜欢
Maybe you'd prefer this one.
可能太小了
Too young, maybe.
这一张呢?
How about this one?
好些了吗? 还没完呢
Better now? But incomplete.
我识破你了 撒旦
Get thee behind me, Satan.
你以为你是谁 竟能区分出善恶?
Who are you to even think you can know the difference between good and evil?
你是上帝吗?
Are you God?
我只是一个信使
I'm just a messenger.
他需要我
He needs me.
你竟然会认为万能的上帝...
How can you imagine that God, the creator of heaven and Earth...
创造万物的神灵...
the source of all life...
可能会需要你?
could possibly need you?
我不知道
I don't know.
他无能到连自己的音讯都没法送?
You don't think He's big enough to deliver His own messages?
你要对我做什么?
What do you want from me?
没什么 我是来放你走的
Nothing. I'm here to set you free.
笑一下 有人来了
I said smile. You have visitors.
勃艮第的公爵
The Duke of Burgundy.
这位就是声名显赫的贞德吧...
So here's the famous Jeanne...
奥尔良的救世主 英国人的噩梦
savior of Orleans, terror of the English.
你要多少赎金 我的国王都会给的
My king will pay any ransom you ask.
你的国王? 是啊 当然
Your king? Oh, yes, of course.
可他付给我什么呢? 是牛? 还是鸡?
What's he gonna pay me with? Cows? Chickens?
我还是喜欢金子 英国人给了我不少
I prefer gold, and the English have plenty.
不知道为了抓住奥尔良的巫婆 他们会付多少钱呢
I wonder how much they'll pay to have the witch of Orleans in their clutches.
英国人一向傲慢 无法接受被一个村姑击败的事实
The English are so arrogant, they can't accept being defeated by a peasant girl.
那肯定是魔鬼干的
It has to have been the devil's work.
是上帝打败了英军
God defeated the English.
那也是上帝让你被俘的?
And God allowed you to be caught?
从个人来说 我不信上帝
Personally, I don't believe in God.
我也不信魔鬼
I don't believe in the devil either.
所以我从来不会失望
That's why I'm never disappointed.
卖了她
Sell her.
为了付贞德的赎金
To payJeanne's ransom.
这是将军们凑的钱 还有奥尔良的百姓
The captains gave what they could, as well as citizens of Orleans.
你们太慷慨了 有多少?
That's very generous of you. How much?
一万金克郎  一万?
Ten thousand gold crowns.  Ten thousand?
真不少啊
That's a lot.
阁下 这件棘手的谈判就由您负责吧
Your Grace, I place you in charge of this very delicate negotiation.
收拾好 你要走了
Get yourself ready. You're leaving.
你是谁?
Who are you?
皮埃尔·戈尚 博韦的主教
Pierre Cauchon, bishop of Beauvais.
既然在我的教区抓获了你 那你的审判由我负责
As you were captured in my diocese, the duty to conduct the trial falls upon me.
审判? 什么审判?
Trial? What trial?
审判你 贞德 异端邪说罪
Your trial,Jeanne, on a charge of heresy.
可是我的国王...
But my king...
他没有付我的赎金?
Didn't he pay my ransom?
似乎英国人比法国人更关心你
It seems the English care more about you than the French.
英国人?  是啊
The English?  Yes.
英国人付了你的赎金
They paid your ransom.
明天你就被送到他们在鲁昂的城堡
Tomorrow you'll be transferred to their great castle at Rouen.
虔诚的英格兰及法兰西国王亨利六世...
Our serene and Christian king, Henry VI, king of England and France...
把这个女孩交给我们 控告她异端邪说罪...
has placed this girl in our hands, accused of heretical deeds...
为了确保审判忠实
to be tried in a matter of faith.
请你手持福音...
Take the Holy Gospels in your hand...
发誓不论回答什么都要诚实
and swear to tell the truth regarding anything you may be asked.
我不知道你要问我什么 可能有些我不想回答
I don't know what you will ask me. You may ask things I won't want to answer.
你要发誓对问你的一切 都要诚实回答
You will swear to tell the truth about everything you are asked.
我愿意诚恳地诉说一切
I will willingly tell the truth about all Earthly things.
可遵照我得到的启示 我只给我的国王一个人讲
But as to my revelations, I've told no one except my king...
查尔斯七世 法兰西唯一的国王
Charles VII, the one and only king of France.
你必须发誓
You must take the oath.
就算是国王也不准拒绝发誓
Not even a king would refuse to take an oath in a matter of faith.
可以告诉你的 我自然会讲
I will tell you all that I'm allowed to tell you.
可至于其他的...
But as for the rest...
就算你杀了我 我也不会说的
even if you threatened to cut off my head, I won't tell you.
那先告诉我们你的名字 这总可以说吧
Begin by telling us your name, assuming you're allowed to tell us that much.
我叫贞德
My name is Jeanne.
我的小十字架被拿走了 可以还给我吗?
My little cross was taken from me. May I have it back?
那你必须先更合作些
Show us a little more cooperation first.
你出生于何处?
Where were you born?
一个叫栋雷米的村子
In a village called Domremy.
你多大了?
How old are you?
十九吧 差不多
Nineteen, or thereabouts.
你入教了吗?
Were you baptized?
是的  那背诵一下天主经
Yes.  Recite our Lord's Prayer.
除非你听我做忏悔
Not unless you hear my confession.
你给我听好了
Listen to me very carefully.
我们都是虔诚的人...
We are all men of faith...
我们会诚心的拯救你和你的灵魂...
and we shall earnestly strive for the salvation of your body and your soul...
教堂的大门永远向迷途知返的人敞开
in the name of our Church who never closes arms to those who return to her.
可如果你不承认我们的评判和权威...
But we cannot help you...
我们就无法帮助你
unless you submit to our learned judgment and authority.
这是给你的提醒...
Take heed of this charitable admonition...
如果你坚持拒绝我们的帮助...
for if you persist in refusing our help...
那我们就不得不把你交给其他部门处理了
we shall have no choice but to abandon you to the secular powers.
等待你的惩罚我想你很清楚
And I think you know well enough the punishment that would await you.
现在...
Now...
你愿意背诵一下天主经吗?
will you please recite our Lord's Prayer?
除非你听我做忏悔
Not unless you hear my confession.
当心 拒绝承认审判对你没有好处的
Be careful. You aren't helping yourself by refusing to submit to our judgment.
你们...
You...
声称是审判我的人 你们才该当心!
who claim to be my judges, you be careful!
早晚有一天你们也会遭到审判的
For you too one day will be judged.
卫兵 把她带走!
Guards, take the prisoner away!
肃静!  她是巫婆!
Silence!  Sorceress!
肃静! 肃静!
Silence! Clear the room!
肃静!
Clear the room!
以后我们要秘密调查 避免受到民众的压力
In future, we should conduct inquiries privately, away from public pressure.
英国人愿意烧死她就烧死她吧 为什么要把我们扯进来呢?
Let the English burn her if they want. Why does it have to involve us?
因为找出她异端的罪证是我们的职责
Because it's our duty to root out heresy wherever we find it.
文森特神父
Father Vincente.
您是我们当中最受人尊敬的人 您怎么看?
You're the most venerable among us. What do you think?
我认为这个审判是假冒的...
I think this trial is a masquerade...
我不会再参与了
and I won't be part of it anymore.
我乐意作她的审判 而不是刽子手
I'm willing to be her judge, but not her executioner.
这一点我会保证
That's what I'm trying to ensure.
判决是在审判结束时下的 戈尚 不是在开始
The verdict comes at the end of a trial, Cauchon. Not at the beginning.
我要回罗马去...
I am going back to Rome...
向教皇报告此事
to give my report to our Holy Father, the Pope.
这太荒谬了 我倒成了被审判的人
This is ridiculous. Now I'm the one who's on trial and being judged.
把他扣起来  你们干什么?
Arrest him.  What are you doing?
这是教会法庭 你们无权这么做
This is an ecclesiastical court. You've no right to do this.
这是在英国的领地
This is English territory.
我有权做任何事
I have the right to do anything.
明白了吗?
Is that clear?
天上的神啊...
Our Father who art in heaven...
请在天堂...
Thy kingdom come...
宽恕我们...宽恕他们...
Forgive us...Forgive them...
宽恕他们吧 宽恕我们吧 宽恕他们吧
Forgive them, then forgive us. Forgive them.
你这是在念叨什么?
Why were you yelling?
你在这儿做什么? 你不能待在这里! 走开!
What are you doing here? You can't stay here! Go away!
为什么? 你在等其他人吗?
Why? Are you waiting for someone else?
是的
Yes.
谁?  我的幻觉
Who?  My visions.
你的幻觉
Your visions.
他们会来这里见你?
They're going to visit you in here?
是的 我是这么恳求的
Yes. That's what I pray for.
我倒想看看 介意我坐在这边吗?
I want to see that. Do you mind if I stay on the side here?
我不会打扰你的  不行!
I won't bother you.  No!
不行! 你不能待在这里!
No, you can't! You can't!
否则他们就不会来了  为什么不会?
Or else they won't come.  Why won't they?
因为我一定要一个人
Because I have to be alone.
算了 反正他们不会来的
Oh. They won't come anyway.
你什么意思 他们不会来吗?  他们为什么来呢?
What do you mean, they won't come?  Why would they?
因为我一直对上帝很忠诚啊...
Because I've always been faithful to God...
他所有的指示我都照做了...
and I've followed everything He's ever said...
他要求的事我都做到了
and I've done everything He's ever asked me to do.
上帝要你做事情?
God asked you to do something?
是的 很多事
Yes, lots of things.
你的意思是 上帝他说...
You mean, God said...
"贞德 我需要你"?
"I need you,Jeanne"?
可他给了我许多征兆
But He's sent me signs.
征兆? 什么征兆?
Signs? What signs?
风 风
The wind. The wind.
风
Wind.
还有云 钟声
And the clouds. Ringing.
钟声 云
Ringing cloud.
跳舞 还有跳舞
The dance. The dance.
剑 田野里的剑
The sword. The sword lying in the field.
那就是征兆
That was a sign.
不 那只是田野里的一把剑
No. That was a sword in a field.
不 不 那是征兆
No. No. That was a sign.
不 那只是田野里的一把剑
No, that was a sword in a field.
可它不会自己跑到那里的
It can't just get there by itself. It can't.
剑不会自己跑到那里的
A sword just doesn't get there by itself.
没错 任何事都会有无数可能 你为何非取其中的一种呢?
True. Every event has an infinite number of causes, so why pick one?
要在田野里出现剑有很多途径
There are many ways a sword might find itself in a field.
看来这种解释不错 那这种呢?
Seems a perfectly valid explanation, but how about this one?
也不错 还有其他可能
Then again, there are other possibilities.
还有更快的
Or even faster.
还没有算其它的
And that's without counting the inexplicable.
有这么多可能 你却偏偏选这个
Yet from an infinite number of possibilities, you had to pick this one.
你看到的不是真相 贞德
You didn't see what was,Jeanne.
你看到的是你想要看的罢了
You saw what you wanted to see.
你说有声音对你说话...
This voice that you say appears to you...
是天使说的还是圣人说的 或者是上帝亲自说的?
is it an angel or a saint, or does it come from God?
我不再跟你说那些了
I won't tell you any more about that.
不是怕回答你 是怕惹怒上帝
I'm more afraid of displeasing Him than not answering you.
你怕说实话会惹怒上帝?
You're afraid of displeasing God by telling the truth?
难道上帝禁止你说实话?
Did God forbid you to tell the truth?
我只跟法国国王说 不是你
My revelations were for the king of France, not for you.
你第一眼看见国王时...
When you saw your king for the first time...
他头顶上有天使在飞吗?
was there an angel over his head?
可能有 我没有看见
If there was one, I did not see it.
没有任何证明 你的国王凭什么相信你?
Why did your king believe in you without any proof?
你问他去
Go ask him yourself.
晚饭
Dinner.
你被抓时 是骑着马吗?
When you were taken prisoner, did you have a horse?
是的 有一半战马血统 黑色的
Yes. A half steed. Black.
马是谁给你的?  国王
Who gave you that horse?  My king.
他给了你多少?
How many did he give you?
五匹战马...
Five steeds...
还有几匹一般的马
and a few hackneys.
不少啊 赶上侯爵们了 真是光荣啊
As much as for a lord. What an honor.
除了这些马 国王还有没有给你其他财富?
Did your king give you other wealth apart from those horses?
那些给你的衣服呢?
What about all those dresses you were given?
是丝绸的 对吗?
Silk dresses, weren't they?
是的
Yes.
是给过我一些
Yes, I was given a few.
可我从没有时间穿
But I never had time to wear them.
作为一个农民来说算很富有了 你有什么好说的?
Still, pretty wealthy for a peasant girl, wouldn't you say?
作为上帝的仆人 你看来也很富有 你有什么好说?
You look pretty wealthy for a servant of God, wouldn't you say?
是你带人进攻巴黎的 是吗?
You launched an attack on Paris, didn't you?
是我
I tried to.
你有没有以上帝的名义...
And didn't you order the citizens of Paris to surrender the city...
命令巴黎的百姓献城投降?
in the name of the King of Heaven?
不 我说 "向法兰西国王投降吧"
No. I said, "Surrender in the name of the king of France."
证据上不是这么写的
That is not what is written in the evidence.
你自己看
Look yourself.
我不识字
I can't read.
我忘了
Yes, I forgot.
上帝竟然派了个不识字的使者来完成这么重要的使命
God sent us an illiterate peasant to carry out such an important mission.
你认为上帝这么做 对吗?
Do you think that God made the right decision?
让一个无知的女孩来拯救法国?
To take an ignorant girl to save the kingdom of France?
这只有上帝能回答
I leave that answer to God.
靠!
Fuck!
冷静一下 大人 求你了
Calm down, my lord. I beg you.
我现在是整个朝廷的笑柄 我怎么冷静得下来?
How can I when I'm made the laughingstock of the whole court?
你也看见了 这女孩对付百姓很有一套...
You've seen how it is. This girl has a way with people...
可我们每天都还是有进展的
but we're making progress every day.
只要这娘们还活着 我们军队就拒绝打仗 你明白么?
As long as that bitch remains alive, our armies refuse to fight. Understand?
他们要确定上帝是站在我们这边
They need proof that God is on their side.
我们不能烧死她 你们才能那么做
It's not for us to burn her. That's your prerogative.
你们的任务就是找出她的罪过!
And it's your prerogative to find her guilty!
除非她承认亵渎了上帝 否则我们不能那么做
But we can't do that unless she admits to blasphemy.
你还等什么?
What are you waiting for?
这城堡里的刑具应有尽有 严刑拷打啊!
You've got a castle full of racks, ropes and pulleys. Torture the bitch!
那样她什么都不会说的
You'll never get anything out of her that way.
还有...
And besides...
我的几个同僚...已经害怕了
you must realize that several of my colleagues are, well, scared.
害怕? 害怕一个女孩?
Scared? Of a girl?
害怕犯错误
Scared to make a mistake.
万一她是对的呢
Suppose she's right.
万一她真是上帝派来的呢
Suppose she has been sent by God.
你站在谁那边 戈尚?  我只站在教会这边
Who's side are you on, Cauchon?  I'm on the side of Holy Mother Church.
你有剑吗?
Do you have a sword?
有不少  你不是还常带着旗吗?
Quite a few.  Didn't you also carry a banner?
是的
Yes.
你更喜欢哪个? 旗还是剑?
Which do you prefer? Your banner or your sword?
我绝对是喜欢我的旗
I was 40 times more fond of my banner.
为什么? 它有什么特殊的价值或者力量?
Why? Did it have some particular value or power?
只是...
It's just...
剑是武器  所以呢?
A sword is a weapon.  And?
所以 我更喜欢旗
And so, I prefer my banner.
为什么?
Why?
我不想杀人
To avoid killing anyone.
你是说如果你没有一直拿着旗的话...
Are you saying if you'd not been carrying your banner...
你就会杀更多的人?
you'd have killed more people?
不是这个意思 我从没有杀过人
Of course not. I never killed anyone.
拿剑时杀人的欲望...
Then perhaps the temptation...
可能就会更强烈吧...
to kill would have been stronger...
非常强烈
too strong, perhaps.
我警告过英国人 让他们撤军
I warned the English to go back home.
我请求他们不要与我们为敌 他们知道我...
I begged them not to force us to fight. They knew that I...
我们有很多证人可以证明...
We have numerous witnesses who can confirm...
你不是一直拿着那面旗的
you were not always carrying your banner.
是的 可能吧
Yes, perhaps.
有时你只拿着你的剑
Sometimes you were carrying just your sword.
是的 我不清楚
Yes. I don't know.
你有没有用过手中的剑呢?
Did you use the sword you held in your hand?
是的 我用过...我把它高高举起...
Yes, I used it...I held it up...
你是把剑高高举起 然后就像这样挥动吧!
You held up your sword and flourished it about like this!
我不记得了
I don't remember.
所以你在战场上 手持利剑...
So, you were on the battlefield with your sword in your hand...
高高的挥舞...
waving it above your head, charging against the enemy...
为了保全性命大声叫嚷着同敌人战斗...
screaming at the enemy, fighting for your life...
而你却要我们相信...
and you expect us to believe...
在这么激烈的过程中...
that in the middle of all this excitement...
你没杀过一个人
you never killed anyone.
是 我没杀过人
No. I never killed anyone.
我不相信 你撒谎了
I can't believe you can lie like that.
我没说谎 没说谎 别烦我 我不记得了
I'm not lying. I'm not lying. Leave me alone. I can't remember.
我没杀过人 我不记得了  那我来帮你回忆一下
I didn't kill anyone. I can't remember.  Let me help your memory.
我不想听了 别烦我 我没有杀那个人
I don't want to hear any more. Leave me alone. I didn't kill that man.
别烦我!
Leave me alone!
停下 停下 我不记得了
Stop. Stop. I can't remember.
战斗昏天暗地的 我只是尽可能的保护好自己
The battles were so confusing. I was only defending myself as best I could.
烟火弥漫 叫喊连天 我又四面受敌
There was so much dust, smoke and noise. I was being attacked on all sides.
可能我是还击了
So maybe perhaps I fought back.
可那只是为了保护自己  看来你想起来了
But it was only to defend myself.  So your memory's coming back.
是的  很好
Yes.  Good.
那你告诉我为什么上帝会让战争爆发呢
Now, you tell me why God let all those battles happen in the first place.
他如此的强大 你还说...
He's so powerful. You said...
"他创造万物 是天地之主"
" He's the creator of heaven and Earth, the source of all life."
他可以轻易地阻止 那些流血和不幸的发生
He could easily have stopped all that blood and misery.
为什么没这么做?
Why didn't He...
是他在散播流血和不幸吗?
Is He the one who spread all that blood and misery?
是他吗?  不是 可他应该阻止这一切的
Is He?  No. But He could have stopped it.
看到我们以他的名义...互相残杀...
What, did he get pleasure...pleasure...
他感到很愉悦吗?
pleasure from watching us killing each other in His name?
以他的名义?
In His name?
是以他的名义 我们以他的名义互相战斗和杀戮...
In His name. We fought and killed in His name...
以上帝的名义  真的吗?
the King of Heaven.  Really?
所有爱我的人哪 跟我冲啊!
Let all those who love me follow me!
"所有爱我的人 跟我冲!"
"Let all who love me follow me!"
哪里提到上帝了?
Where does God get mentioned?
算了吧 贞德
Come on,Jeanne.
诚实些吧
Be honest.
你是为你自己而战 以自己的名义而战
You fought for yourself. In your name.
不是的!
No!
我只是尽可能的在保护自己
I was defending myself as best as I could.
保护自己是没有错的 不是吗?
Everyone has the right to defend themselves, don't they?
是的 应该这样! 难道我要让自己去死吗?
Yes, they do! Should I have let myself get killed?
要那样吗?  不 你做的很好
Is that it?  No. You did fine.
甚至说做的很棒
I'd even say well done.
事实上...
As a matter of fact...
那你认为那些被你杀的人也是罪有应得了?
most of the ones you killed probably deserved it, don't you think?
我从来不认为杀戮能换来和平
I never thought killing each other would bring about any peace.
我同意
I agree.
只有跟英国人战斗才能换来和平
Peace will only be got from the English at the end of a lance.
我不同意 你的想法为什么变来变去呢?
I don't agree. Why do you keep changing your mind all the time?
是你 为什么...
You. Why...
你为什么要这么对我?
Why are you doing this to me?
伤害我 你感到很快乐吗?
Do you get pleasure from hurting me?
快乐 真是个难以定义的词汇
Pleasure. That's a difficult word to define.
痛苦何时结束? 快乐何时开始? 你的快乐是何时开始的?
When does pain end and pleasure begin? When did your pleasure begin?
是你手持利剑的时候吗?
With that sword in your hand?
伤害其他人...
I never took pleasure...
我从不会感到快乐
in hurting anyone.
真的吗?
Really?
放我走吧 放我走吧
Set me free. Set me free.
会的 贞德
You will be,Jeanne.
会的
You will be.
贞德 我最亲爱的教友...
Jeanne, my very dear friend in Christ...
所有审判员
we, your judges and assessors...
渴望得出一个真实公正的判决...
desirous of reaching a true and lawful verdict...
所以把你的审判发到巴黎大学...
submitted a transcript of your trial to the University of Paris...
征求了他们的意见
to attain their opinion.
经过慎重考虑...
After careful consideration...
学者们跟我们一致认定...
the learned scholars have concluded with us...
你已犯下多项重大罪行
that you have committed many grievous sins.
现在我要你仔细听他们的意见...
I ask you now to listen most carefully...
具体如下
to their opinion, as detailed in these articles.
罪行一
Article One.
你自称是上帝命令你穿男人的衣服...
You said that by God's command you have continually worn men's clothes...
剪成男人的短发...
and that you have also worn your hair short...
无法将你同你的敌人分辨出来
with nothing to distinguish you from the soldiers with whom you fought.
请不要遗弃我
Don't abandon me. Please.
您在哪里?
Where are You?
您在哪里啊?
Where are You? Please.
这就是您想要的吗?
Is this what You want?
您想要我...
You want me to...
在还没有...
to burn...
做忏悔的情况下...
without...
就被烧死吗?
being confessed?
最后 罪行十二
Finally, Article 1 2.
声称不愿服从...
You have said that you are not willing to submit yourself...
教会法庭的审判 只服从上帝
to the judgment of the church militant, but only to God.
对于这一点 学者们认为...
As to this article, the scholars say...
你藐视教会的权威
that you have no comprehension of the authority of the Church.
在信仰上你已误入歧途...
That you have perniciously erred in the faith of God...
追随迷信 偏离信仰...
and you are a child of superstition, a wanderer from the faith...
祈求和崇拜魔鬼...
an invoker of demons, an idolater...
是个异端邪说者
and a heretic.
我们再一次诚恳地劝告你...
We once again admonish, beg and exalt you...
放弃你错误的信仰吧...
to cast out and recant your erroneous beliefs...
在悔过书上签名吧
by signing this recantation.
签吧
Please.
如果教会...
If the Church...
想要我说...
wants me to say...
我所见的都是邪恶的...
that my visions are evil...
那我宁愿不相信这个教会
then I do not believe in this Church.
让你的人做准备
Perform your office.
等等
Wait.
贞德 我求你了 签吧
Jeanne, I beg of you, sign.
看在上帝的份上 你不明白吗? 我这是在救你啊
In God's name, don't you understand? I'm trying to save you.
我想要做忏悔
I want to be confessed.
签了这个 你愿意的话我帮你做忏悔
Sign this and I will confess you myself, if you want.
那我可以...
And may I...
我可以去做弥撒吗?
May I go to Mass?
只要你愿意
As often as you like.
为了上帝 签了吧
Now, for the love of God, sign.
签了吧 贞德 这能让你免于枷锁
Sign,Jeanne, and you'll be free of your chains.
免于火刑 贞德
Free of the fire,Jeanne.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道你刚才签的是什么吗?
Do you know what you just signed?
你签字放弃了"他是存在的"这一信念
You just signed away His existence.
我不是这个意思  你认为 他是个骗子
I didn't mean to.  For you, He's a lie.
一切都是幻觉
An illusion.
不 不
No, no.
他说我可以做忏悔的
He told me that I would be confessed.
可你最终还是抛弃了他
In the end, it was you who abandoned Him.
能再给我一下吗?  没什么好后悔的
May I have that back, please?  You have nothing to regret.
还给我!
Give it back to me!
还给我!  带她走!
Give it back!  Take her away!
让她闭嘴!
Silence her!
给 她已经放弃了邪恶的信仰
There. She has recanted.
并且我们接受她的悔过...
And we accept her repentance...
教会的大门永远向迷途知返的人敞开
for the Church never closes her arms to those who would return to the fold.
是否处死她是你的事 不是我们的了
Now she's your martyr, not ours.
不要!
Please!
可以了
Enough.
给
Here.
想穿衣服的话就试试这身吧
If you want to get dressed, try these for size.
大主教
My lord bishop.
您自己看看
Come to see for yourself.
你来看
Well, take a look.
看见了吗? 又换成男人打扮了
You see? Dressed as a man again.
看来悔过不顶什么用啊?
Her touching repentance didn't last very long, did it?
桑利斯的主教刚巧路过 他目击了一切
The Bishop of Senlis was passing by and was on hand to witness her relapse.
凭空出现那衣服可真是奇迹啊?
And by what miracle did these clothes find their way in here?
那不是神迹 亲爱的戈尚
Not a miracle, my dear Cauchon.
是邪恶的魔咒
An evil spell.
那女孩是巫婆 明天要施以火刑
This girl is a witch, and tomorrow she will burn for it.
在菜市口做好准备
Have the stake prepared in the marketplace.
贞德 我真是不明白 你为什么要这么做?
Jeanne, I don't understand. Why did you do it?
为什么啊?  那你呢
Why?  And you.
为什么要撒谎?
Why did you lie?
你答应我要听我忏悔的
You promised to have me confessed.
我知道 可那是当时为了救你
I know. It was the only way to have you saved from the fire.
我要救的不是我的身躯
It's not my body I want to save.
而是我的灵魂
It's my soul.
我只求你一件事
I ask only one thing.
请听我做忏悔
Please, hear my confession.
不行 贞德 我不能听你做忏悔
I can't,Jeanne. I can't hear your confession.
非常抱歉
I'm very sorry.
你要做忏悔?
You want to confess?
我在听啊
I'm listening.
主啊 我有罪
I've committed sins, my Lord.
很多的罪
So many sins.
我看见了那么多的征兆
I saw so many signs.
那么多"征兆"
Many signs.
那些我想看见的
The ones I wanted to see.
我战斗...
I fought...
是因为仇恨...
out of revenge...
和绝望
and despair.
是我...
I was all the things...
让人们相信...
that people believe...
上帝允许他们...
they're allowed to be...
允许他们...
when they're fighting for...
为了理想而战
a cause.
为了理想
For a cause.
我很...
I was...
自豪...
proud...
也很...
and...
固执
stubborn.
自私
Selfish.
是的 还有残忍
Yes. Cruel.
是的
Yes.
残忍
Cruel.
你做好准备了么?
You think you are ready now?
是的
Yes.
很好
Good.
贞德于1431年5月30日死于火刑 当时年仅19岁
五百年后被罗马教廷追封为"圣女"